火箭很大，但很少有人知道到底多大
Rockets are big, but no one seems to really know just how big these rockets are
因为我们看到的电视上的火箭
and that's because any time we're showing these rockets
要么单独一根摆在那
they're always just kind of like by themselves
要么在天上飞，要么旁边一座没见过的楼，要么在船上
or flying through the air or next to a big building or even on a big boat
很少有机会能让你根据某些参照物知道火箭到底有多大
You really get a good opportunity to get some visual context for how friggin big these rockets are
当前太空叉的猎鹰九号火箭高度是230英尺（70米）
For instance the SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket is 230 feet tall
但这到底是多高？
but what does that mean?
所以今天让你康康平常见不到的画面
So today I'm going to show you what you'll never get to see in real life
借助特效技术，我要把火箭放到一些日常场景中
Using visual effects, I'm going to put these rockets in everyday places so that we can all gain
从而给大家这些火箭大小的直观感受
a better appreciation of the scale of these giant bottles that fly into space
首先我们康康猎鹰九号的着陆腿有多大
To begin, let's take a look at the Falcon 9 landing legs here
在图片或者视频里你们可能以为也就这么大吧
And in pictures and videos they seem kind of dinky like
maybe they're about this big or so
实际上它有29英尺（8.8米）长
Whereas in reality there are 29 feet in length
当从墙（箭体）上展开时
and when unfolded from the wall
它能伸出24英尺（7.3米）远，作为对比，我们这房顶只有17英尺（5.2米）高
they will reach out 24 feet and to put that into perspective our ceiling is only 17 feet tall
我们工作室都放不下一整条着陆腿
These legs literally do not fit in our studio
这是否给你一点大小的概念呢？
And this begins to give you a sense of scale
就像我刚说的，猎鹰九号高230英尺（70米）
So like I said the Falcon 9 rocket is 230 feet tall meaning that
大概是21层楼
it's about the height of a 21 storey building
但我所在的楼只有七层
But the roof that I'm standing on right now is only seven stories tall
所以我现在高度应该在火箭三分之一处，然后你就仰望吧
that puts me about a third of the way up the rocket, and it just keeps going up
这还不是太空叉最大的火箭
And this isn't even the biggest rocket that SpaceX makes
他们还有个推力更大的重型猎鹰
They have a more powerful one called the Falcon Heavy
相当于三个猎鹰九号摆在一起，虽然高度一样，但推力大多了
which is basically just three Falcon 9s put together so it's the same height but way more powerful
目前重型猎鹰只发射过一次，就是那辆著名的特斯拉
So far they've only had a single test flight, famously putting a Tesla Roadster
轨道最远到小行星带，绕着太阳还能转几十亿年吧
out into the asteroid belt, hood over the Sun for the next billion or so years
而因为猎鹰九号太高了，所以乍一看特别苗条
And because these rockets are so tall, they appear to be kind of thin
但你离近了看，你会发现真不是这样
But as usual, when you start getting closer to them, their size becomes apparent
因为猎鹰九号直径12英尺（3.66米）
because they are 12 feet in diameter
里面能竖着站下两个我
I could literally stand on top of myself and still fit on the inside of one of these rockets
同时，太空叉还在造更大的火箭
But here's the thing SpaceX is developing a much much larger rocket
因为他们带更多货物去更遥远的太空，比如殖民火星
because they need something that can go really far into space
but also carry a lot of weight while they're doing it, like to Mars, like a colony to Mars
那个更大的火箭就是BFR——“大”“猎鹰”“火箭”
So that's what they're making next, the BFR, which stands for Big Falcon Rocket
因为它真的很大
because it's really Falcon (Fxxking) big
BFR高348英尺（106米），比自由女神像还要高
At 348 feet tall, the BFR is taller than the Statue of Liberty
就算自由女神上面再横着放一个重型猎鹰
Even if you were to lay the Falcon Heavy sideways on top of the Statue
也没有BFR高
it still wouldn't be as tall as the BFR
这火箭真的老大了，直径30英尺（9.14米），比伦敦的巴士还要长
This rocket is truly massive, with the 30-foot-diameter, it's as wide as a London bus is long
你光看上面级的燃料罐你就知道了
I mean just look at the fuel tank that's gonna sit in the upper spaceship part of the rocket
在2018年中，这火箭应该还不存在，除了马一龙的PPT里
As of mid 2018 this rocket doesn't technically exist yet except for the drawing board
或者像本视频这样的CG里
and in CG renderings like this
但它真长这样，真的这么大
But this is it, this is what its gonna look like
乐观估计这火箭三年内就能上天，保守估计六年内吧
In fact I believe they want to get this up and flying within three years, maybe six years definitely
随着火箭越来越大，将来我们可能还会看见更大的火箭
And as big as these rockets are, we may someday see rockets that are even larger
你看，BFR都没有送人类去月球的土星五号大
I mean the BFR is still not as large as the Saturn 5 rocket which took us to the moon
而土星五号是50年前的玩意了
and we built that 50 years ago
最后我还想感叹一下，这么大的东西竟然还能跑的比谁都快
In the end I just find it crazy that these structures are some of the fastest vehicles humanity has ever made
要知道，去太空不止是要往上飞
because going into space is not just simply a matter of going up
而是要先往上飞，然后横着飞，速度快到沿着地球的弧线往下掉才行
it's a matter of going up and then sideways so fast that you just continue to fall around the earth
而这个速度是17000mph（27359km/h），相当于海平面的22马赫
and those speeds are 17,000 miles an hour, at sea level that is Mach 22
感谢观看，超喜欢做这类视频的
Thanks for watching this video, it's a pretty fun experiment to make
如果你喜欢的话我或许会做更多
and if you liked it I think I might try making more of these
别忘了分享点赞投币关注收藏
In the meantime try sharing this video with your friends
分享的时候你可以先问问他们心中火箭有多大
and asking them first how big that they think rockets are
因为我猜他们很有可能低估了火箭的大小
because I'm willing to bet they're gonna underestimate it
原视频来自YouTube频道“Corridor Crew”，字幕翻译给虫
If you're new here try subscribing to the Corridor Crew
up主有很多航空航天的科普字幕
we got all kinds of crazy cool content coming your way from DIY builds
带你提高致己的姿势水平
It's a cool science experiments like this to the old-school behind-the-scenes content
that you've always loved and enjoyed